<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hubble Space Telescope on Space Telescope Pictures</title>
    <link>/categories/hubble-space-telescope/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hubble Space Telescope on Space Telescope Pictures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/hubble-space-telescope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Gets a Celestial Boost</title>
      <link>/hubble-gets-a-celestial-boost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hubble-gets-a-celestial-boost/</guid>
      <description>The NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope doesn’t usually get much assistance from its celestial subjects — but to take this image, the telescope opted for teamwork and made good use of a fascinating cosmic phenomenon known as gravitational lensing. This effect works when the gravitational influence of a massive object, such as the galaxy cluster in this image, is so colossal that it warps the surrounding space, causing nearby light to travel along distorted paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Accidentally Discovers a New Galaxy in Cosmic Neighborhoo</title>
      <link>/hubble-accidentally-discovers-a-new-galaxy-in-cosmic-neighborhoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hubble-accidentally-discovers-a-new-galaxy-in-cosmic-neighborhoo/</guid>
      <description>This is a Hubble Space Telescope image of a concentration of stars within the globular cluster NGC 6752. Hidden among the stars is an image of a background galaxy that is much farther away. The diminutive galaxy, named by its discoverers as Bedin 1, measures only around 3,000 light-years at its greatest extent — a fraction of the size of the Milky Way. Not only is it tiny, but it is also incredibly faint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA&#39;s Hubble Spots Embryonic Galaxy SPT0615-JD</title>
      <link>/nasas-hubble-spots-embryonic-galaxy-spt0615-jd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nasas-hubble-spots-embryonic-galaxy-spt0615-jd/</guid>
      <description>This Hubble Space Telescope image shows the farthest galaxy yet seen in an image that has been stretched and amplified by a phenomenon called gravitational lensing. The embryonic galaxy, named SPT0615-JD, existed when the universe was just 500 million years old. Though a few other primitive galaxies have been seen at this early epoch, they have essentially all looked like red dots, given their small size and tremendous distances. However, in this case, the gravitational field of a massive foreground galaxy cluster, called SPT-CL J0615-5746, not only amplified the light from the background galaxy but also smeared the image of it into an arc (about 2 arcseconds long).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lopsided Lynx</title>
      <link>/a-lopsided-lynx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-lopsided-lynx/</guid>
      <description>This galaxy, known as NGC 2337, resides 25 million light-years away in the constellation of Lynx. NGC 2337 is an irregular galaxy, meaning that it — along with a quarter of all galaxies in the Universe — lacks a distinct, regular appearance. The galaxy was discovered in 1877 by the French astronomer Édouard Stephan who, in the same year, discovered the galactic group Stephan’s Quintet (heic0910i). Although irregular galaxies may never win a beauty prize when competing with their more symmetrical spiral and elliptical peers, astronomers consider them to be very important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artist&#39;s Concept of Exoplanet HR 8799b</title>
      <link>/artists-concept-of-exoplanet-hr-8799b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artists-concept-of-exoplanet-hr-8799b/</guid>
      <description>Release Date April 1, 2009 This is an artistic illustration of the giant planet HR 8799b. The planet was first discovered in 2007 at the Gemini North observatory. It was identified in the NICMOS archival data in a follow-up search of NICMOS archival data to see if Hubble had also serendipitously imaged it. The planet is young and hot, at a temperature of 1500 degrees Fahrenheit. It is slightly larger than Jupiter and may be at least seven times more massive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barred Spiral Galaxy</title>
      <link>/barred-spiral-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/barred-spiral-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>Barred Spiral Galaxy NGC 1300 Credit: NASA, ESA, and The Hubble Heritage Team (STScI/AURA) Acknowledgment: P. Knezek (WIYN) The Hubble Space Telescope is a project of international cooperation between NASA and the European Space Agency. NASA&amp;rsquo;s Goddard Space Flight Center manages the telescope. The Space Telescope Science Institute conducts Hubble science operations. Goddard is responsible for HST project management, including mission and science operations, servicing missions, and all associated development activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carina Nebula Detail</title>
      <link>/carina-nebula-detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/carina-nebula-detail/</guid>
      <description>Carina Nebula Details: Great Clouds Credit for Hubble Image: NASA, ESA, N. Smith (University of California, Berkeley), and The Hubble Heritage Team (STScI/AURA) Credit for CTIO Image: N. Smith (University of California, Berkeley) and NOAO/AURA/NSF The Hubble Space Telescope is a project of international cooperation between NASA and the European Space Agency. NASA&amp;rsquo;s Goddard Space Flight Center manages the telescope. The Space Telescope Science Institute conducts Hubble science operations. Goddard is responsible for HST project management, including mission and science operations, servicing missions, and all associated development activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat&#39;s Eye Nebula</title>
      <link>/cats-eye-nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cats-eye-nebula/</guid>
      <description>The Cat&amp;rsquo;s Eye Nebula, one of the first planetary nebulae discovered, also has one of the most complex forms known to this kind of nebula. Eleven rings, or shells, of gas make up the Cat&amp;rsquo;s Eye. The full beauty of the Cat&amp;rsquo;s Eye Nebula is revealed in this detailed view from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Hubble Space Telescope. The image from Hubble&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Camera for Surveys (ACS) shows a bull&amp;rsquo;s eye pattern of eleven or even more concentric rings, or shells, around the Cat&amp;rsquo;s Eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crab Nebula</title>
      <link>/crab-nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crab-nebula/</guid>
      <description>The Crab Nebula is a supernova remnant, all that remains of a tremendous stellar explosion. Observers in China and Japan recorded the supernova nearly 1,000 years ago, in 1054. Credit: NASA, ESA, J. Hester and A. Loll (Arizona State University) The Hubble Space Telescope is a project of international cooperation between NASA and the European Space Agency. NASA&amp;rsquo;s Goddard Space Flight Center manages the telescope. The Space Telescope Science Institute conducts Hubble science operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Sees Stars and a Stripe in Celestial Fireworks</title>
      <link>/hubble-sees-stars-and-a-stripe-in-celestial-fireworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hubble-sees-stars-and-a-stripe-in-celestial-fireworks/</guid>
      <description>Release date: July 1, 2008 This image is a composite of visible (or optical), radio, and X-ray data of the full shell of the supernova remnant from SN 1006. The radio data show much of the extent that the X-ray image shows. In contrast, only a small linear filament in the northwest corner of the shell is visible in the optical data. The object has an angular size of roughly 30 arcminutes (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Space Telescope</title>
      <link>/hubble-space-telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hubble-space-telescope/</guid>
      <description>The Hubble Space Telescope in a picture snapped by a Servicing Mission 4 crewmember just after the Space Shuttle Atlantis captured Hubble with its robotic arm on May 13, 2009, beginning the mission to upgrade and repair the telescope. The Hubble Space Telescope is a project of international cooperation between NASA and the European Space Agency. NASA&amp;rsquo;s Goddard Space Flight Center manages the telescope. The Space Telescope Science Institute conducts Hubble science operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubble Uncovers a Galaxy Pair Coming in from the Wilderness</title>
      <link>/hubble-uncovers-a-galaxy-pair-coming-in-from-the-wilderness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hubble-uncovers-a-galaxy-pair-coming-in-from-the-wilderness/</guid>
      <description>NASA’s Hubble Space Telescope uncovered two tiny dwarf galaxies that have wandered from a vast cosmic wilderness into a nearby “big city” packed with galaxies. After being idle for billions of years, they are ready to party by starting a firestorm of star birth. Hubble captured the glow of new stars in these small, ancient galaxies, called Pisces A and Pisces B. Observations suggests the galaxies are late bloomers because they have spent most of their existence in the Local Void, a region of the universe sparsely populated with galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Echo</title>
      <link>/light-echo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/light-echo/</guid>
      <description>&amp;quot;Light Echo&amp;quot; Illuminates Dust Around Supergiant Star V838 Monocerotis (V838 Mon) Credit: NASA and The Hubble Heritage Team (AURA/STScI) The Hubble Space Telescope is a project of international cooperation between NASA and the European Space Agency. NASA&amp;rsquo;s Goddard Space Flight Center manages the telescope. The Space Telescope Science Institute conducts Hubble science operations. Goddard is responsible for HST project management, including mission and science operations, servicing missions, and all associated development activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Space Telescopes See Weather Patterns in Brown Dwarf</title>
      <link>/nasa-space-telescopes-see-weather-patterns-in-brown-dwarf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nasa-space-telescopes-see-weather-patterns-in-brown-dwarf/</guid>
      <description>JANUARY 8, 2013: Astronomers using NASA&amp;rsquo;s Hubble and Spitzer space telescopes have probed the stormy atmosphere of a brown dwarf named 2MASSJ22282889-431026, creating the most detailed &amp;quot;weather map&amp;quot; yet for this class of cool, star-like orbs. The forecast shows wind-driven, planet-sized clouds enshrouding these strange worlds. Brown dwarfs form out of condensing gas, as stars do, but lack the mass to fuse atoms and produce energy. Instead, these objects, which some call failed stars, are more similar to gas planets with their complex, varied atmospheres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Telescopes Help Discover Surprisingly Young Galaxy</title>
      <link>/nasa-telescopes-help-discover-surprisingly-young-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nasa-telescopes-help-discover-surprisingly-young-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>NASA image release April 12, 2011 Astronomers have uncovered one of the youngest galaxies in the distant universe, with stars that formed 13.5 billion years ago, a mere 200 million years after the Big Bang. The finding addresses questions about when the first galaxies arose, and how the early universe evolved. NASA&amp;rsquo;s Hubble Space Telescope was the first to spot the newfound galaxy. Detailed observations from the W.M. Keck Observatory on Mauna Kea in Hawaii revealed the observed light dates to when the universe was only 950 million years old; the universe formed about 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA&#39;s Hubble Celebrates 21st Anniversary with &#34;Rose&#34; of Galaxies</title>
      <link>/nasas-hubble-celebrates-21st-anniversary-with-rose-of-galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nasas-hubble-celebrates-21st-anniversary-with-rose-of-galaxies/</guid>
      <description>NASA image release April 20, 2011 To see a video of this image go here: www.flickr.com/photos/gsfc/5637796622To celebrate the 21st anniversary of the Hubble Space Telescope&amp;rsquo;s deployment into space, astronomers at the Space Telescope Science Institute in Baltimore, Md., pointed Hubble&amp;rsquo;s eye at an especially photogenic pair of interacting galaxies called Arp 273. The larger of the spiral galaxies, known as UGC 1810, has a disk that is distorted into a rose-like shape by the gravitational tidal pull of the companion galaxy below it, known as UGC 1813.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturn&#39;s Rings in Ultraviolet Light</title>
      <link>/saturns-rings-in-ultraviolet-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/saturns-rings-in-ultraviolet-light/</guid>
      <description>Saturn&amp;rsquo;s Rings in Ultraviolet Light Credit: NASA and E. Karkoschka (University of Arizona) The Hubble Space Telescope is a project of international cooperation between NASA and the European Space Agency. NASA&amp;rsquo;s Goddard Space Flight Center manages the telescope. The Space Telescope Science Institute conducts Hubble science operations. Goddard is responsible for HST project management, including mission and science operations, servicing missions, and all associated development activities. To learn more about the Hubble Space Telescope go here: www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive Star Goes Out With a Whimper Instead of a Bang</title>
      <link>/massive-star-goes-out-with-a-whimper-instead-of-a-bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/massive-star-goes-out-with-a-whimper-instead-of-a-bang/</guid>
      <description>This pair of visible-light and near-infrared photos from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Hubble Space Telescope shows the giant star N6946-BH1 before and after it vanished out of sight by imploding to form a black hole. The left image shows the star, which is 25 times the mass of our sun, as it looked in 2007. In 2009, the star shot up in brightness to become over 1 million times more luminous than our sun for several months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Lair at the Heart of Galaxy NGC 1068</title>
      <link>/hidden-lair-at-the-heart-of-galaxy-ngc-1068/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hidden-lair-at-the-heart-of-galaxy-ngc-1068/</guid>
      <description>Galaxy NGC 1068 can be seen in close-up in this view from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Hubble Space Telescope. NuSTAR&amp;rsquo;s high-energy X-rays eyes were able to obtain the best view yet into the hidden lair of the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s central, supermassive black hole. This active black hole &amp;ndash; shown as an illustration in the zoomed-in inset &amp;ndash; is one of the most obscured known, meaning that it is surrounded by extremely thick clouds of gas and dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NuSTAR View of Galaxy NGC 1068</title>
      <link>/nustar-view-of-galaxy-ngc-1068/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 16:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nustar-view-of-galaxy-ngc-1068/</guid>
      <description>Galaxy NGC 1068 is shown in visible light and X-rays in this composite image. High-energy X-rays (magenta) captured by NASA&amp;rsquo;s Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array, or NuSTAR, are overlaid on visible-light images from both NASA&amp;rsquo;s Hubble Space Telescope and the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. The X-ray light is coming from an active supermassive black hole, also known as a quasar, in the center of the galaxy. This supermassive black hole has been extensively studied due to its relatively close proximity to our galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers Set a New Galaxy Distance Record</title>
      <link>/astronomers-set-a-new-galaxy-distance-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/astronomers-set-a-new-galaxy-distance-record/</guid>
      <description>This is a Hubble Space Telescope image of the farthest spectroscopically confirmed galaxy observed to date (inset). It was identified in this Hubble image of a field of galaxies in the CANDELS survey (Cosmic Assembly Near-infrared Deep Extragalactic Legacy Survey). NASA’s Spitzer Space Telescope also observed the unique galaxy. The W. M. Keck Observatory was used to obtain a spectroscopic redshift (z=7.7), extending the previous redshift record. Measurements of the stretching of light, or redshift, give the most reliable distances to other galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultraviolet Ring Around the Galaxies</title>
      <link>/ultraviolet-ring-around-the-galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 17:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ultraviolet-ring-around-the-galaxies/</guid>
      <description>Astronomers have found unexpected rings and arcs of ultraviolet light around a selection of galaxies, four of which are shown here as viewed by NASA and the European Space Agency Hubble Space Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Chandra X-Ray Observatory</title>
      <link>/history-of-chandra-x-ray-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/history-of-chandra-x-ray-observatory/</guid>
      <description>This image of the galaxy cluster Abell 2125, provided by the Chandra X-Ray Observatory (CXO), reveals several massive multimillion degree Celsius gas clouds that appear to be in the process of merging. Ten of the point-like sources are associated with galaxies in the cluster and the rest are probably distant background galaxies. The small bright feature in the extreme lower right-hand corner is probably a background galaxy cluster not associated with Abell 2125.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Science</title>
      <link>/space-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/space-science/</guid>
      <description>Released to commemorate the 14th anniversary of NASA’s Hubble Space Telescope (HST) is the image of a galaxy cataloged as AM 0644-741. Resembling a diamond encrusted bracelet, the ring of brilliant blue star clusters wraps around a yellowish nucleus of what was once a normal spiral galaxy. Located 300 million light years away in the direction of the southern constellation Dorado, the sparkling blue ring is 150,000 light years in diameter, making it larger than our entire home galaxy, the Milky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge-on Galaxy</title>
      <link>/edge-on-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 1999 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/edge-on-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>NASA Hubble Space Telescope has imaged an unusual edge-on galaxy, revealing remarkable details of its warped dusty disc and showing how colliding galaxies trigger the birth of new stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy NGC 4013</title>
      <link>/galaxy-ngc-4013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 1999 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-ngc-4013/</guid>
      <description>An amazing edge-on view of a spiral galaxy 55 million light years from Earth has been captured by the Hubble Space Telescope. The image reveals in great detail huge clouds of dust and gas extending along and above the galaxy main disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starburst Galaxy NGC 3310</title>
      <link>/starburst-galaxy-ngc-3310/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 1999 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/starburst-galaxy-ngc-3310/</guid>
      <description>Scientists using NASA Hubble Space Telescope are studying the colors of star clusters to determine the age and history of starburst galaxies, a technique somewhat similar to the process of learning the age of a tree by counting its rings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whirlpool Galaxy</title>
      <link>/whirlpool-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 1999 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/whirlpool-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>The image from NASA Hubble Telescope shows spiral arms and dust clouds in the nearby Whirlpool galaxy. Visible starlight and light from the emission of glowing hydrogen is seen, which is associated with the most luminous young stars in the spiral arms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy NGC 1850</title>
      <link>/galaxy-ngc-1850/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 1999 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-ngc-1850/</guid>
      <description>By spying on a neighboring galaxy, NASA Hubble Space Telescope has captured an image of a young, globular-like star cluster—a type of object unknown in our Milky Way Galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy M82</title>
      <link>/galaxy-m82/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 1999 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-m82/</guid>
      <description>A colorful image showing violent star formation triggered when two galaxies bumped into each other has been captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy NGC 3079</title>
      <link>/galaxy-ngc-3079/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 1999 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-ngc-3079/</guid>
      <description>A lumpy bubble of hot gas rises from a cauldron of glowing matter in a distant galaxy, as seen by NASA Hubble Space Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backwards Spiral Galaxy</title>
      <link>/backwards-spiral-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 1999 00:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/backwards-spiral-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>Astronomers using NASA Hubble Space Telescope have found a spiral galaxy that may rotate in the opposite direction from what was expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy NGC 1512</title>
      <link>/galaxy-ngc-1512/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 1999 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galaxy-ngc-1512/</guid>
      <description>A rainbow of colors is captured in the center of a magnificent barred spiral galaxy, as witnessed by the three cameras of NASA Hubble Space Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postflight - Apollo XII - MSC</title>
      <link>/postflight-apollo-xii-msc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 1969 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/postflight-apollo-xii-msc/</guid>
      <description>S69-60424 (29 Nov. 1969) &amp;mdash; Astronaut Charles Conrad Jr., commander of the Apollo 12 lunar landing mission, holds two lunar rocks which were among the samples brought back from the moon by the Apollo 12 astronauts. The samples are under scientific examination in the Manned Spacecraft Center&amp;rsquo;s Lunar Receiving Laboratory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>