<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spitzer Space Telescope on Space Telescope Pictures</title>
    <link>/categories/spitzer-space-telescope/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spitzer Space Telescope on Space Telescope Pictures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/spitzer-space-telescope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arp 142 The Penguin and the Egg</title>
      <link>/arp-142-the-penguin-and-the-egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/arp-142-the-penguin-and-the-egg/</guid>
      <description>This image of distant interacting galaxies, known collectively as Arp 142, bears an uncanny resemblance to a penguin guarding an egg. Data from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Spitzer and Hubble space telescopes have been combined to show these dramatic galaxies in light that spans the visible and infrared parts of the spectrum. This dramatic pairing shows two galaxies that couldn&amp;rsquo;t look more different as their mutual gravitational attraction slowly drags them closer together. The &amp;ldquo;penguin&amp;rdquo; part of the pair, NGC 2336, was probably once a relatively normal-looking spiral galaxy, flattened like a pancake with smoothly symmetric spiral arms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Feeds the Beast in a Galaxy Cluster?</title>
      <link>/what-feeds-the-beast-in-a-galaxy-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 16:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what-feeds-the-beast-in-a-galaxy-cluster/</guid>
      <description>A massive cluster of galaxies, called SpARCS1049+56, can be seen in this multi-wavelength view from NASA Hubble and Spitzer space telescopes. At the middle of the picture is the largest, central member of the family of galaxies (upper right red dot of central pair). Unlike other central galaxies in clusters, this one is bursting with the birth of new stars. Scientists say this star birth was triggered by a collision between a smaller galaxy and the giant, central galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Helix Nebula Unraveling at the Seams</title>
      <link>/the-helix-nebula-unraveling-at-the-seams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 21:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-helix-nebula-unraveling-at-the-seams/</guid>
      <description>This image from NASA Spitzer and GALEX shows the Helix nebula, a dying star throwing a cosmic tantrum. In death, the star dusty outer layers are unraveling into space, glowing from the intense UV radiation being pumped out by the hot stellar core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of the End of Star Formation</title>
      <link>/the-beginning-of-the-end-of-star-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 20:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-beginning-of-the-end-of-star-formation/</guid>
      <description>Time is running out for the galaxy NGC 3801, seen in this composite image from NASA Galaxy Evolution Explorer and other instruments combining light from across the spectrum, ranging from ultraviolet to radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galactic Train Wrecks</title>
      <link>/galactic-train-wrecks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/galactic-train-wrecks/</guid>
      <description>This montage combines observations from NASA Spitzer Space Telescope and NASA Galaxy Evolution Explorer GALEX spacecraft showing three examples of colliding galaxies from a new photo atlas of galactic train wrecks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Galaxy Mission Celebrates Sixth Anniversary</title>
      <link>/nasa-galaxy-mission-celebrates-sixth-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 20:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/nasa-galaxy-mission-celebrates-sixth-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>NASA Galaxy Evolution Explorer Mission celebrates its sixth anniversary studying galaxies beyond our Milky Way through its sensitive ultraviolet telescope, the only such far-ultraviolet detector in space. The mission studies the shape, brightness, size and distance of distant galaxies across 10 billion years of cosmic history, giving scientists a wealth of data to help us better understand the origins of the universe. One such object is pictured here, the galaxy NGC598, more commonly known as M33.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Classic Beauty</title>
      <link>/a-classic-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 17:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-classic-beauty/</guid>
      <description>A composite image of M51, also known as the Whirlpool Galaxy, shows the majesty of its structure in a dramatic new way through several of NASA orbiting observatories</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M81 Galaxy is Pretty in Pink</title>
      <link>/m81-galaxy-is-pretty-in-pink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 22:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/m81-galaxy-is-pretty-in-pink/</guid>
      <description>The perfectly picturesque spiral galaxy known as Messier 81, or M81, looks sharp in this new composite from NASA Spitzer and Hubble space telescopes and NASA Galaxy Evolution Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Older Galaxy Pair Has Surprisingly Youthful Glow</title>
      <link>/older-galaxy-pair-has-surprisingly-youthful-glow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 20:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/older-galaxy-pair-has-surprisingly-youthful-glow/</guid>
      <description>NASA Galaxy Evolution Explorer and Spitzer Space Telescope combined to show a pair of interacting galaxies might be experiencing the galactic equivalent of a mid-life crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing Andromeda Galaxy</title>
      <link>/amazing-andromeda-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2006 23:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/amazing-andromeda-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>The many personalities of our great galactic neighbor, the Andromeda galaxy, are exposed in this new composite image from NASA Galaxy Evolution Explorer and Spitzer Space Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Observatories Present Rainbow of a Galaxy</title>
      <link>/great-observatories-present-rainbow-of-a-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2006 13:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/great-observatories-present-rainbow-of-a-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>NASA Spitzer, Hubble and Chandra space observatories teamed up to create this multi-wavelength, false-colored view of the M82 galaxy. The lively portrait celebrates Hubble weet sixteen birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Stellar Ripple</title>
      <link>/a-stellar-ripple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2006 13:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-stellar-ripple/</guid>
      <description>This false-color composite image shows the Cartwheel galaxy as seen by NASA Galaxy Evolution Explorer, where the first ripple appears as an ultraviolet-bright blue outer ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysterious Blob Galaxies Revealed</title>
      <link>/mysterious-blob-galaxies-revealed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2005 17:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mysterious-blob-galaxies-revealed/</guid>
      <description>This image composite shows a giant galactic blob (red) and the three merging galaxies NASA&amp;rsquo;s Spitzer Space Telescope discovered within it (yellow). Blobs are intensely glowing clouds of hot hydrogen gas that envelop faraway galaxies. They are about 10 times as large as the galaxies they surround. Visible-light images reveal the vast extent of blobs, but don&amp;rsquo;t provide much information about their host galaxies. Using its heat-seeking infrared eyes, Spitzer was able to see the dusty galaxies tucked inside one well-known blob located 11 billion light-years away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire within the Antennae Galaxies</title>
      <link>/fire-within-the-antennae-galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2004 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fire-within-the-antennae-galaxies/</guid>
      <description>This false-color image composite from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Spitzer Space Telescope reveals hidden populations of newborn stars at the heart of the colliding &amp;ldquo;Antennae&amp;rdquo; galaxies. These two galaxies, known individually as NGC 4038 and 4039, are located around 68 million light-years away and have been merging together for about the last 800 million years. The latest Spitzer observations provide a snapshot of the tremendous burst of star formation triggered in the process of this collision, particularly at the site where the two galaxies overlap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life at the Intersection of Colliding Galaxies</title>
      <link>/life-at-the-intersection-of-colliding-galaxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2004 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/life-at-the-intersection-of-colliding-galaxies/</guid>
      <description>This false-color image from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Spitzer Space Telescope reveals hidden populations of newborn stars at the heart of the colliding &amp;ldquo;Antennae&amp;rdquo; galaxies. These two galaxies, known individually as NGC 4038 and 4039, are located around 68 million light-years away and have been merging together for about the last 800 million years. The latest Spitzer observations provide a snapshot of the tremendous burst of star formation triggered in the process of this collision, particularly at the site where the two galaxies overlap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissection of a Galaxy</title>
      <link>/dissection-of-a-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2004 20:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dissection-of-a-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, the best way to understand how something works is to take it apart. The same is true for galaxies like NGC 300, which NASA&amp;rsquo;s Spitzer Space Telescope has divided into its various parts. NGC 300 is a face-on spiral galaxy located 7.5 million light-years away in the southern constellation Sculptor. This false-color image taken by the infrared array camera on Spitzer readily distinguishes the main star component of the galaxy (blue) from its dusty spiral arms (red).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Hubble Space Telescope (HST)</title>
      <link>/history-of-hubble-space-telescope-hst/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/history-of-hubble-space-telescope-hst/</guid>
      <description>The razor sharp eye of the Hubble Space Telescope (HST) easily resolves the Sombrero galaxy, Messier 104 (M104). 50,000 light-years across, the galaxy is located 28 million light-years from Earth at the southern edge of the rich Virgo cluster of galaxies. Equivalent to 800 billion suns, Sombrero is one of the most massive objects in that group. The hallmark of Sombrero is a brilliant white, bulbous core encircled by the thick dust lanes comprising the spiral structure of the galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>